Ignacio Ordovás Pascual

Data Scientist

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ordovaspascual/

Phone: +34 607 59 36 55

Email: ordovaspascual@gmail.com
Web: https://ordovas.github.io/

I have many years of scientific experience and I've recently started to work in a professional consulting environment where I'm involved in cross functional clients projects as well as several internal projects involving Machine Learning pipelines. My experience helps me apply skills like teamwork, meeting deadlines, and communicating results and complex ideas effectively to a non-technical audience. I am a curious and fast learner of the latest techniques in data science.

EXPERIENCE

COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS, Madrid: Associate Data Scientist (Apr 2021 - Present)

Participated in projects involving different topics as Life Sciences, Insurance, Food quality control and Oil & Gas companies. Some examples of my work are listed below:

Life Sciences client project

- Updated AI model to help study designers to create less burdensome clinical trials.
- Analyzed the effects of variables in patient burden using survey data, by applying statistical techniques like Causal Inference/Propensity Score and Bootstrapping.
- Built a new DevOps solution for a project, by designing a CI/CD in GitHub that connects input data from S3 buckets and automatically deploys the containerized updated model.
- Ensured stability and maintainability of the AI algorithms deployed in production using Unit tests.

Other client and internal projects experience

- Created PoC demos for clients in an Azure Web App using Docker/Streamlit or Flask.
- Built solutions to detect defects in objects of interest (using autoencoders or clustering, among other approaches).
- Developed an object detection application in the Azure Percept IoT device.
- Compiled a proposal of solutions using ML methods (e.g. Random Forest) and data analytics, identifying the most relevant actions to optimize the outcome.
- Collaborated with Data Engineers to create API endpoints to productionize solutions.

INSTITUTE OF PHYSICS OF CANTABRIA (CSIC-UC), Santander: Researcher (Jan 2014 - Dec 2019)

Studied the relation between the optical extinction, X-ray absorption and classification of Active Galactic Nuclei.

- Analyzed galaxy spectral datasets to conduct a PhD research project.
- Created Python code for automatic model selection and feature detection.
- Planned numerical simulations to measure physical parameters.

EDUCATION

PhD In Science and Technology (Merit with distinction *Cum Laude*): University of Cantabria, *Santander*, (Dec 2013 - Dec 2019) Master in Astrophysics: University of La Laguna, *La Laguna*, (Sep 2012 - Jul 2013) Bachelor Degree in Physics: University of La Laguna, *La Laguna*, (Sep 2005 - Sep 2012)

LANGUAGES

English B2 (University of Cambridge), Spanish (Native)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced Python Programming	Statistical Analysis	Machine Learning	Git
CI/CD Pipelines	Natural Language Processing	Cloud (Azure, AWS)	Computer Vision

SOFT SKILLS

Public speaking	Teamwork	Storytelling	Versatility
Written communication	Problem solving	Mentoring	Critical thinking

OTHER HIGHLIGHTS

Communication of scientific results: 4 peer-reviewed papers, 7 oral presentations and 3 scientific posters **Certification:** Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)

Ironhack Data Analytics Bootcamp: Private education company course to learn Data Science applied to real use cases.

MOOC courses in Udemy and Coursera: CI/CD, CV, NLP, Keras/Tensorflow, Azure, AWS, Machine Learning.

Narrate the Science. Scenic and Oral Narration Techniques for Scientific Communication, UC summer course.